Finding aid to the Agnes Hunt Papers CA.MS.00155
Smith College Archives
Agnes Hunt Papers
1897-1946
1900-1923
Smith College Archives
Hunt, Agnes, 1876-1923
CA.MS.00155
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
Professor of History and poet. Contains biographical material, correspondence, poetry, photographs, publications and tributes.
Biographical / Historical
Agnes Hunt was born in Manchester, New Hampshire on April 1, 1876 to Nathan Parker Hunt and Elizabeth S. (Bisbee) Hunt. She graduated from the Manchester High School in 1893. She earned an A.B. at Smith College where she excelled in history and was the author of the "Ivy Song" for her graduating class of 1897. She continued to study history at Yale University where she received her Ph.D. in 1900. Her doctoral thesis was titled, "The Provincial Committees of Safety."
Her first teaching post was as an instructor in history at the College for Women at Western Reserve University in Cleveland, Ohio where she lived and worked in a settlement house. In 1903 she became Associate Professor of History at Wells College in Aurora, New York. Then in 1906 after spending a year abroad she returned to Smith College as an Associate Professor of History, where she taught English History and the history of Latin America. Known as an accomplished poet her work appeared in Massachusetts, New Hampshire and New York newspapers. She was also inducted into the Zeta Chapter of the Phi Beta Kappa Society of Massachusetts and was published in professional teaching journals.
In 1919 Professor Hunt resigned from Smith College and returned home to New Hampshire to care for her mother. After her mother's death, she remained at home and became an active member of the Manchester community with memberships and affiliations to many civic and professional organizations until her death in 1923.
Scope and Contents
The materials document the life and career of Agnes Hunt as a member of the History Department. The papers include biographical material, correspondence, poetry, photographs, publications and tributes from 1897 until 1946. The bulk dates of materials range from 1900 to 1923. Notable correspondents include Ada Comstock, the first woman Dean of Smith College and later President of Radcliffe College. In a letter to Professor Hunt written in 1922 she proposed a plan for an American Association of University Women, exhorting college women to make themselves "guardians of educational interests."
Related Material
Faculty collections for Professor Hunt's peers in the History, as well as the English, Greek, and Music departments can also be found in the Smith College Archives.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Agnes Hunt Papers were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Hunt, Agnes, 1876-1923
- Contest Flyer: Colonial Monographs, 1923 (Box 874, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - Abel, Anne Heloise, 1919 (Box 874, Folder 2)
- Correspondence - Basset, John Spencer, 1919 (Box 874, Folder 3)
- Correspondence - Bliss, Laura Adella, 1914 (Box 874, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - Booth, Mrs. R.P., 1946 (Box 874, Folder 5)
- Correspondence - Comstock, Ada Louise, 1922 (Box 874, Folder 6)
- Correspondence - Dean, Sidney Norton, 1913-19 (Box 874, Folder 7)
- Correspondence - DeWoolf, Elliott, 1915 (Box 874, Folder 8)
- Correspondence - Hanscom, Elizabeth D., 1926 (Box 874, Folder 9)
- Correspondence - Hazen, Charles Downer, 1900 (Box 874, Folder 10)
- Correspondence - Hildt, John C., 1908-20 (Box 874, Folder 11)
- Correspondence - Moog, Wilson T., undated (Box 874, Folder 12)
- Correspondence - Neilson, William Allen, 1919 (Box 874, Folder 13)
- Correspondence - Roman, Fiederick, 1912 (Box 874, Folder 14)
- Correspondence - Tyler, Amelia Whiting, undated (Box 874, Folder 15)
- Degree: Yale, 1900 (Box 874, Folder 16)
- Memorial Book, 1923 (Box 874, Folder 17)
- Memorial Book, 1923 (Box 874, Folder 18)
- Operetta, 1904 (Box 874, Folder 19)
- Photographs (3), undated (Box 874, Folder 20)
- Publications, 1904-24 (Box 874, Folder 21)
- Sorority Cards, 1911 (Box 874, Folder 22)